CLANCY ROSE: All right, so now we are going to move on to mixing your breve, unless you already have just a quart of--or you already have some half and half ready and then steaming the milk for the double breve latte.
So, I am going to mix that, just equal portions, half whole milk and half heavy whipping cream, which is going to make half and half or breve.
And I am going to fill that up in the pitcher.
I am using a 14-ounce cup, so I am going to fill up the milk to the pitcher to about this ridge.
This is how much milk you should use.
I am going to begin the steaming process.
What I do is I do the steaming in three motions.
The first is positioning the pitcher around the steam wand, in such a way--at an angle to where when you turn the steam wand on, the milk starts swirling around in a circle inside the steaming pitcher.
I do that until the milk temperature kind of matches the temperature of my hand, it is about 100 degrees, and you just kind of feel this warm break in the milk.
Then you are going to drop down the pitcher so that the tip of the steam wand is just right at or right above the surface of the milk.
You are going to hear air start to being introduced into the milk, and what you are doing is creating foam at that point.
And with breve, since it contains more fat, we are going to want to stretch it for longer.
So, for breve latte, I am going to be stretching for about seven or eight seconds and then I am going to push this pitcher back up and get it at the right angle again so that it is spinning around inside the pitcher again and keep that up until it is at the temperature that I want the milk.